# **Lucio Franco**

Currently a Computer Science student at the University of Denver, I have a strong passion for learning, solving problems and programming. I like producing clean code, designing/architecting projects, and researching different technologies for those projects. I have experience writing APIs, Games, and Web Apps. I am very interested in distributed systems, databases and functional programming.

2225 Buchtel Blvd #202, Denver, CO, 80210 (240)-688-6461 lucio.franco@du.edu https://luciofran.co https://github.com/LucioFranco

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **ReadyTalk,** Denver, CO — Software Engineer Intern

https://readytalk.com JUN 2016 - AUG 2016

Architected a bot that used NLP to summarize slack channels.

## **Ombud,** Denver, CO — Software Engineer Intern

https://ombud.com

MAR 2015 - OCT 2015

Worked as the 4th member of the engineering team that built the web application for answering RFPs. Learned node/react/elasticsearch.

## **EDUCATION**

## **University of Denver,** Denver, CO — Honors Bachelors of Science in Computer Science

SEPT 2014 - MAY 2018 | GPA: 3.33

Courses: Algorithms & Data Structures, Parallel & Distributed Programming,
Database Organization & Management, Systems Programming, Game Networking

#### **PROJECTS**

Below are two of my more notable projects; there are many more completed or in progress on my personal site! <a href="https://luciofran.co/#projects">https://luciofran.co/#projects</a>

## **cobalt.rs** – Static site generator

Static site generator built in Rust. I am a member of the organization and am an active contributor. github.com/cobalt-org

## **Amethyst** — Data oriented game engine

Data oriented game engine written in Rust. I am a member of the organization and am active contributor. github.com/amethyst

## **SKILLS**

**Expert:** Rust, Java, C/C++, JavaScript, Git, HTML/CSS, React.js, Docker, Postgres

Intermediate: Ruby, Mysql, Unix, Bash, CI/CD, OpenGL, Hadoop, HDFS, Public Speaking, AWS, DigitalOcean

**Beginner:** Go, ElasticSearch, Haskell

#### **AWARDS**

2nd place at Startup Weekend DU

3rd place at Codeday Boulder

Walter Johnson High School Computer Science Award

#### **LANGUAGES**

English(Native)

French(fluent)

Italian(Semi-fluent)